RESUME OBJECTIVE

Front end developer with 5+ years experience working with React/Redux and HTML/CSS/JS developing and maintaining web applications across an array of industries. Self-taught programmer that strives for innovation and continued education. Proven ability to produce quality code, optimize overall flow and improve UI experience.

EXPERIENCE

October 2021 – October 2022 | Shift4, Allentown, PA

Software Engineer III

- Maintained and developed front end code for POS application used in secure bulk purchase transactions (e.g. Theme parks, Hotels, Stadiums)
- Developed contemporary layouts for devices including tablets and phones
- Improved UI experience based on user feedback for multiple software versions ranging in complexity

July 2019 – October 2021 | Cadent, Philadelphia, PA

Associate Front-End Engineer

- Built shared React components for ad time purchasing app using React/Redux and ensured code functionality with Jest
- Fixed bugs from existing codebases and implemented enhancements to improve speed and functionality
- Explored modern is technology including sagas and web sockets

December 2017 – September 2018 | Project One, Philadelphia, PA **Junior Front-End Developer**

- Led the front-end development of an innovative web app for college students to learn and practice calculus
- Built a fully functioning MVP for higher education from the ground up
- Utilized burgeoning is libraries such as immutableJS and semanticUI

Feb – May 2017 | Thomas Jefferson University Hospital, Philadelphia, PA **CS Intern**

 Developed an fMRI post-processing toolbox using Matlab/Python that adjusts for respiratory changes during image acquisition.

- 856 304 8167
- Danieln.Faro@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/daniel-faro-4a4024101/
- 912 North Genesee Ave West Hollywood, CA 90046
- www.DanFaro.com

EDUCATION

2011

Lehigh University, Bethlehem, PA

M.S. Environmental Engineering

2010

Lehigh University, Bethlehem, PA

B.S. Chemical Engineering

SKILLS

React / Redux

HTML / CSS / JS

LESS/SASS

Redux-Saga / Axios

MaterialUI / SemanticUI

Firebase / MongoDB / Postgres

Node.js / Django

Jest / Mocha

TypeScript

Python

SOL